Jeremiah S. Custard Papers
Jeremiah S. Custard Papers
1879-1976
Custard, Jeremiah S., 1862-1931.
1 linear ft.
Papers of the Methodist clergyman. Papers include diaries and pastoral records (1879-1931), including sermons; personal and church financial records (1899-1929); and a biographical sketch and genealogy by Mary and George Custard, 1976.
148922
Biographical History
Jeremiah S. Custard (1862-1931) was an American Methodist clergyman. Born in Bartonsville, Monroe County, Pennsylvania, he attended public schools and then studied at the Collegiate Institute at Stroudsburg, and Fairview Academy. He was converted at eighteen years of age. On December 10, 1884, he married Miss Lizzie Shiffer of Hamilton, Jefferson County, Pa. He served as supply preacher eight years before joining the Wyoming Conference in 1894. His pastorates included: 1898-1900, Skinner's Eddy; 1901, Springville; 1902-03, Clark's Summit.
[Adapted from Chaffee, Amasa Franklin. History of the Wyoming Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church. New York: Eaton & Mains, 1904, page 309.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Jeremiah S. Custard Papers are divided into three series: Biographical data, Diaries and pastoral records, and Financial records.
Biographical data contains a photocopied typescript of Custard's biography written in 1976 by Mary and George Custard as a college graduation present for their daughter Alice. The text includes photocopies of news clippings and photographs and a detailed genealogy of the Custard family.
Diaries and pastoral records includes pocketsized books arranged chronologically which trace Custard's career as a Methodist minister. Besides personal items, the books contain records of church membership, sermons delivered, pastoral acts (marriages, baptisms, funerals), financial statements, pastoral visits, etc.
The Financial records contain information on Custard's personal expenditures for insurance, housing, taxes, Christmas presents, music lessons, his children's education, food, fuel and utilities, etc. This series also contains an account book for the Summit Methodist Episcopal Church and parsonage debt subscription list (1904-1906).
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Custard, Jeremiah S., 1862-1931.; Custard family -- Genealogy.; Clergy -- United States.; Methodist Church -- Clergy.; Account books.; Diaries.; Genealogies (histories); Sermons.; Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gifts of several Custard family members, 1967-1978.
Inventory
- Biographical data
  - "Through a Glass, Darkly: The Life and Times of Jeremiah S. Custard", 1976 (Box 1)
- Diaries and pastoral records
  - 1879-1881, 1884, 1889-1892 (Box 1)
  - 1890, 1892, 1894-1899 (Box 1)
  - 1900-1902 (Box 1)
  - 1903-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1905-1907 (Box 1)
  - 1907-1911 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1913 (Box 1)
  - 1914-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1916-1917 (Box 1)
  - 1918-1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - 1922-1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924-1925 (Box 1)
  - 1926-1927 (Box 1)
  - 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 2)
- Financial records
  - 1899-1929 (Box 2)